

# Rian Arthur Rutherford

Email - rianrutherford@outlook.com LinkedIn Portfolio Website

## About Me

Languages - English | Specialisation - Unreal Engine | Country - England, UK

I started programming in 2016 and did it as a hobby for 5 years. I then transitioned to make it my profession in 2021, while in my final year of college, just before starting university.

After my first year at Falmouth University, I decided to specialise in Unreal Engine 5 and multiplayer games. My Goal now is to gain experience and mentorship working on multiplayer gameplay and networking systems in UE5, and other proprietary game engines.

### Education

BA(Hons) Game Development: Programming

Falmouth University, England; 2021 - 2024

Level 3 Computing BTEC Extended Diploma

Weston College, England; 2019 - 2021

Skills

**Programming Languages** 

C++ | Rust | Blueprints | Python | GDScript | C#

**Game Engines** 

Unreal Engine | Godot | Unity

## Work Experience

Blockception: Nov 2017 - Nov 2022

Freelance programmer at Blockception making Minecraft Maps.

Made: The Moa'ul Mountain, Dragon's Tale, and Mountain Retreat.

Weston Place Agency: Sept 2020 - May 2021

Website design team leader at Weston Place Agency. Responsibility: manage design team and website production.

Oracle Falls: Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

Credited volunteer game tester on Oracle Falls by Evil Robot Empire.

### Interests

I like playing Dungeons & Dragons, watching anime, and occasionally playing video games; RTS and MMO are my favorite game genres.

Most recently I enjoyed playing Homeworld: Deserts of Kharak and Higan: Eruthyll.

Some of my favorite animes are: The Misfit of Demon King Academy, Gate, and BOFURI.

## Projects

Cyberturn: Sept 2022 - May 2023

Six person University project. Turn-based game made in Unreal Engine 5. Core systems programmer: worked on AI and tile movement system.

The Organic Route: Feb 2023

Unreal Engine 5 game made by four person team for the global game jam.

Demise: Dec 2022

Multiplayer game made in Unreal Engine 5 in one week. Worked as a solo developer.

Knight Watch: Jul 2022

Unreal Engine 5 game made in one week for a game jam. Team leader of the eight person team.

Sentinel: Jan 2022

2D game made in Godot 3 for a game jam, uses 3rd party assets. Worked as a solo developer.

LANSpace: Oct 2021

Multiplayer 2D game made using Python 3 and PyGame. Worked as a solo developer.